Jordi Riera

Software Developer at MPC

kender.jr@gmail.com

Summary

Technical Director with deep interest in rendering and technical support to artist, with creating friendly user tools.

My experience get me in different fields but my primary expertise is animation movies.

Software side, I mainly use Maya, Softimage, Renderman and Mentalray.

I am fluent in scripting with Python and pyQt, for creation of minor tools or for prototyping for dev. Proficient with Windows, MacOs and Linux distributions.

Best quote: 'Fail is an option, fear is not' J.Cameron

Specialties

Pipeline, Rendering, Lighting, Compositing, Shading Maya, XSI, MentalRay, Renderman, Python, pyQt, Shell Scripting.

Experience

Software Developer at MPC

August 2010 - Present (5 months)

Pipeline ProTech Department: support to artist and short term development.

-- Python, Maya, Lua, Shell, PyQt

Owner at CGStudioMap.com

March 2010 - Present (10 months)

CGStudioMap.com is a website gathering and sharing informations about CG studios all around the world

--

Self Employed at Kenderland

July 2008 - Present (2 years 6 months)

Technical Director, Head Hunting, Career Advisor

Technical Director (TD) at Animation Lab

January 2010 - April 2010 (4 months)

Working on feature animation movie "P.L.A.N.T.S"

Creation of friendly user tools for lighting department (layer manager, link manager, rig of lights (spot light, point light etc)) according to artists requests.

-- Maya, Liquid, 3delight, Python, PyQt

5 recommendations available upon request

Technical Director (TD) at Cube Creative Computer Company

November 2009 - December 2009 (2 months)

Speaker at University of Bordeaux and Remote work as Scripting operator

-- XSI, Python

Technical Director (TD) at nWave Digital

January 2009 - September 2009 (9 months)

Work for stereoscopic feature movie "Samy's adventure: The secret passage".

Technical Director for Lighting, Compositing and Shading without direct supervise but in direct contact with lighting, shading and compositing supervisors and production to priorities their requests of retakes, improvement of shots (artistically and technically), creation of tools and wrangling shots on the farm

-- Maya, 3Delight, PRM, Fusion, Python and Mel -- Credited in Lighting Development 6 recommendations available upon request

Lighting Artist at nWave Digital

October 2008 - January 2009 (4 months)

Work for stereoscopic feature movie "Samy's adventure: The secret passage". Lighting Artist for character and set lighting following supervisor/lead requests. Creation of needed layers for compositing department. Creation of lighting rigs for characters

-- Maya, 3Delight, PRM

Technical Director (TD) at m.a.r.k.13

August 2008 - September 2008 (2 months)

Firefighter on a short deadline show video for Daimler (28 working days in 1 month, project finished 2 days before deadline)

In charge of shading, lighting, and rendering (set up of passes, optimization, wrangling, scripting, managing answers for 2d Artists asks)

-- XSI, MentalRay, AfterEffect, VUE

2 recommendations available upon request

Lighting TD at Pinka Studio

March 2008 - April 2008 (2 months)

Set up the lighting and the rendering for the pilot of Elasto and Culbuto, a TV HD animation series. Set up, in collaboration of TDs, the automation of the lighting/compositing process

-- XSI, MentalRay

Ligthing Rendering Compositing at Antefilms Studio

November 2006 - June 2007 (8 months)

Lighting n Rendering Division for the 4th season of Code Lyoko, a 2D/3D TV Animation Series. More than 300 shots in 8 months.

-- XSI, MentalRay, Fusion

2 recommendations available upon request

Speaker at Les Deux Mystères

2003 - 2006 (3 years)

Member of this CG association as student first then as speaker.

1 recommendation available upon request

3D Generalist at Mad-Cox

May 2005 - July 2005 (3 months)

Intership of Archi Viz

-- Lightwave, FPrime

Education

ESTEI

Licence, General CG (Print, web, 3D), 2002 - 2005

Interests

professional networking (CG Studios, Head hunting, recruitment) everything around pictures (painting, photography, CG)
Pipelines, scripting, Efficiency
Conferences (SIGGRAPH, FMX)

Guitar player, snooker, card games, video games, sciences, theater, philosophy international travels

Jordi Riera

Software Developer at MPC

kender.jr@gmail.com



16 people have recommended Jordi

"Jordi worked as a lighting TD at Animation Lab for about 6 months. Although Jordi may come across as a quiet individual he proved to be a very confident professional. Jordi had to relocate for this position to a complete new country and cultural environment. Jordi was very responsive and helped us run the relocation process smoothly. Not only did Jordi proved to be a true professional lighting TD but was extremely helpful in supporting the recruiting efforts at Animation Lab via his extensive connections in the industry. I wish Jordi every success in future endeavors and truly am looking forward to working with him in the future!"

— Yael Ran, Recruitment Manager, Animation Lab, worked with Jordi at Animation Lab

"Jordi joined Animation Lab as we were preparing to scale up our lighting department and their respective toolsets. His work was invaluable in the support and tools he provided for lighting, shading, and rendering- showing a deep knowledge and understanding of a Renderman production pipeline. I would strongly recommend Jordi to any studio looking for a strong and valuable Renderman TD."

— Matteo Shapira, CG Supervisor, Animation Lab, managed Jordi indirectly at Animation Lab

"I enjoyed working with Jordi. He is dedicated to his work and does an excellent job supporting the artists. He is self managed and has great communication skills that assist him in communicating well both with the team as well as with the artists he is supporting. Jordi quickly understood the pipeline at Animation Lab and used this knowledge in designing and developing new tools that were both efficient and user friendly. Jordi contributed greatly to the team. I look forward to work with him again."

— Jami Levesque, Supervising TD, Animation Lab, managed Jordi at Animation Lab

"Jordi was a lighting TD at Animationlab, he got lots of skills and he is a good team player. On the period Jordi was working with us he created many tools in a very short time, tools that will help us to achieve our LOF. I will be happy to have Jordi back on the team the moment will need again his excellent work again. Good luck Jordi in wherever you'll go. Ittai"

— **Ittai Arbel**, producer, animationlab, managed Jordi indirectly at Animation Lab

"I'm working with Jordi for a few month and I am amazed every day. As the head of the lighting department, I asked Jordi for a list of tools that we needed. Jordi is creating graet tools for my team, all are easy to use and are working great. he is open to listen to my remarks, gives his own inputs, and contantly improving the tools. Jordi is very "user friendly" and a great member of "animationlab"."

— Haim Sarusi, Head Of Lighting, Animationlab, worked directly with Jordi at Animation Lab

"Jordy was a great help in the production of "Around the world in 50 years". I really appreciated his constant will to improve the pipline and find solutions to fix recurrent problems. Thanks to him, on one hand we have new tools that improved greatly the efficiency of the work reviewing process, and on the other hand the lighters could focus more on the lighting work because Jordy took over a significant part of the technical tasks for the lighting département. It was a good experience to work with Jordi and I would be pleased to work with him in the future."

— Boris de Moffarts, compositing supervisor and artist, Nwave digital, managed Jordi indirectly at nWave Digital

"Jordi is always keen on learning new things and keeping himself up-to-date with tools and technologies. While very open-minded, he is practical and serious when the job needs to be done. He likes to explore new possibilities and doesn't stay stucked with what he already knows. He is really eager to learn more, understand better and broaden his knowledge and experience. Always in a good mood and fun, it is really nice to work with him."

— **Hugues De Keyzer**, *Graphics Software Developer*, *nWave Digital*, worked directly with Jordi at nWave Digital

"Jordi gained a good professional culture of pipeline with his experience and meetings like at Siggraphs (OMG three already). He revealed problems and suggested solutions with an objective analysis. His tools matched with all our needs and allowed us our productivity. He quickly debugged 3D scenes when lighters didn't know what to do, and all compositor liked that."

— David Mazeau, Stereoscopic Compositor, nWave Digital, worked with Jordi at nWave Digital

"An enthusiastic, skilled TD, Jordi had to multi-task for several departments and was always eager to participate in problem solving. He was particularly helpful in creating tools and providing technical support for lighting and compositing."

— Lynn Cohen, Line Producer, nWave Digital, managed Jordi indirectly at nWave Digital

"Jordi is a great worker. Find a solution for any problems is his rule and it's a pleasure to work with him. He was a real added-value to help to finish the production in time, and he found so many solutions to accelerate the production. Hope i will work with him again."

— Remi TAGLIAMONTE, Stereoscopy Compositor, nWave Digital, worked with Jordi at nWave

Digital

"Jordi did a very good job as a TD, he creates few scripts that was very usefull to the compositing department at Nwave. He managed retakes very fast and very well, that's why I directly go to see him when I needed one (and he probably hate me for that) I will be really happy to work again with him."

— Alban Kasikci, 3D Compositor, nWave Digital, worked with Jordi at nWave Digital

"realy cool guy with a lot of skills. worked in scedual and time and delivered outstanding results"

- Holger Weiss, was Jordi's client

"jordi was always on shedule, on point creative-wise and fun to work with. go get him!!!!"

— **Dominique Schuchmann**, was Jordi's client

"Good technical skills, a great knowledge about lighting. Good team spirit, interested and he easily helps his team. His behaviour is appreciated."

— Carl Bouchon, Lead Render/Lighter, Antefilms Studio, managed Jordi at Antefilms Studio

"Great skill in rendering and compositing technique. He always stay aware about new technology and new Lot of motivations and energy in his work. He learn and share with the team, it's really appreciable to have him in the group."

— Vincent Courbis-Poncet, Ligthing Compositing, moonscoop Antefilm, worked directly with Jordi at Antefilms Studio

"As 3D and lighting teacher of Jordi Riera, I strongly recommend him for working as Lighter Technical Director. His strong experience, both at school and in 3D production companies, make him particularly able to feel what kind and lights are needed according to objects shading and artistic requirements. Thanks to his knowledge in using 3D software, like XSI, and his scripting ability, he is not only able to find a solution to a problem, but also to make it available and easy to use for people working on the project. Jordi would be a valuable addition to your production staff, making me and your company proud of his talents."

- François Gastaldo, was Jordi's client

Contact Jordi on LinkedIn